Guide to the H. David Kaplan Schlumberger Well Services Collection
University of Houston Libraries
H. David Kaplan Schlumberger Well Services Collection
1970-1976
2007-021
Kaplan, H. David; Schlumberger Well Services
0.50 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The H. David Kaplan Schlumberger Well Services Collection contains information ranging from 1970-1976.
Biographical Information:
H. David Kaplan was born in Brooklyn, New York on November 13, 1934. In 1956, he received a B.A. in journalism from The University of Michigan. Kaplan has worked for newspapers, magazines, and corporate communications while also functioning as a patron of and volunteer to the arts throughout the United States.
Kaplan's longstanding interest in the performing/fine arts was established by his parents, and was further entrenched when he lived in New York City. Another influence on his interest in the arts was his uncle, Al Kaplan, who performed in vaudeville throughout the world from 1920-1947.
Kaplan has provided many years of service to the arts through his involvement with the Houston Grand Opera, in his former role as Associate Publisher for Houston’s Performing Arts Magazine, and in his ongoing role as an instructor in Enjoying Opera and American Opera courses for continuing education classes in Federal Way, Washington. He has also enhanced the arts collections of several libraries, donating this collection as well as portions of the Hoblitzelle Theatre Collection to the University of Texas, Austin, and a 48-volume collection of New York City theatre playbills and programs to the University of Washington Libraries’ Special Collections. He continues his enthusiastic patronage of the arts, and routinely donates New York theater programs to the University of Washington Libraries Special Collections.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Schlumberger Well Services
Genre/Form of Material:
Awards; Brochures; Correspondence; Publications (document genre); Typescripts
Geographic Name:
Houston (Tex.) -- History
Acquisition Information:
H. David Kaplan, 2007
Separated Materials:
The publications have been cataloged, and can be located in the UH Library catalog by searching: Schlumberger Sonde Off, Houston Schlumberger Recorder, and Schlumberger Manager.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
The H. David Kaplan Schlumberger Well Services Collection contains information ranging from 1970-1976. Consisting of a single box, this collection includes: employee handbooks and insurance information, awards and certificates, presentations and training materials, an assortment of publications about Schlumberger, and personal and employee correspondence. The publications have been cataloged, and can be located in the UH Library catalog by searching: Schlumberger Sonde Off, Houston Schlumberger Recorder, and Schlumberger Manager.
Detailed List of Contents
- Employee Information
  - Schlumberger career information brochures (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Schlumberger Employee Credit Union (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Schlumberger Employment Agreement and Employee Handbook (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Medical insurance information (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Performance evaluation for H. David Kaplan (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1970-1976
  - Incoming correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Employee Memorandums, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Presentations, 1970-1976
  - Information Meeting "Petroleum Lifeline", December 14-18, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Service Awards Presentation, January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Breakfast Club Presentation, March 3, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cased Hole Services, March 22-26, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Perforating Movie, June 21-25, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Introduction of President Magne by C. A. Rosenthal and Service Award Speech, January 12, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Credit Union Annual Meeting, W.J. Gillingham, Janary 19, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Truck Movie Script for training purposes, March 6-10, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Engineer Training, October 16-20, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - For Recruiters., August 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Field District, November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - First Aid, July 8-12, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Information Meeting E.R.I.S.A. (Employee Retirement Income Security Act), March 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Awards and Certificates, 1970-1976
  - IABC Award of Excellence, May 3, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - IABC Award of Honorable Mention, May 3, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Houston Art Directors Club Show: Award of Excellence, October 16, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - IABC Appreciation Certificate, January 1971-December 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - IABC Certificate of Membership, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - IABC Award of Merit, April 3, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Indiana University Audio Visual Institute Certificate of Recognition, October 27, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - IABC Certificate of Appreciation, January 1972-December 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Program Learning Workshop Certificate of Completion, March 18-23, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - IABC Certificate of Appreciation, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - IABC 5W's Awards Program Certificate of Recognition and Second Place Special Project, June 23, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Junior Achievement Advisor Certificate of Appreciation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous Publications
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 1, Folder 33)